Lake Ridge, Virginia, USA durgakundu888@gmail.com +1 571 866 0054

# **DURGA KUNDU**

US CITIZEN

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Engineer II, 6+ Years Of Experience, 5th Place Hackathon Winner at Atlassian's ShipIt of 400 Hackathon Teams, 60+ Certifications, Forbes 30 Under 30 2019 Summit Scholar, Grace Hopper Celebration 2020 Scholar, Passionate About Learning And Mentoring.

#### LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Projects</u>

Stack Overflow CodePen

## **EDUCATION**

JAN. 2023 - AUG. 2023

#### Introduction to Cyber Security Specialization, New York University, New York, NY

Specialization taught by former Chief Security Officer @ AT&T and Professor, Dr. Edward Amoroso.

Courses: Introduction to Cyber Attacks, Cyber Attack Countermeasures, Real-Time Cyber Threat Detection and Mitigation, Enterprise and Infrastructure Security

JAN, 2023 - AUG, 2023

#### Building Cloud Computing Solutions at Scale Specialization, Duke University, Durham, NC

Specialization taught by Data Science Professor, Noah Gift.

Courses: Cloud Computing Foundations; Cloud Virtualization, Containers and APIs; Cloud Data Engineering; Cloud Machine Learning Engineering and MLOps

Projects: Continuous Delivery Pipeline for an AWS Website, Serverless Data Engineering Pipeline, Deploy a Flask Machine Learning Model to a Cloud Platform, Containerized Flask ML Microservice

Topics: Cloud Computing, API Development, Data Science, Data Engineering, Machine Learning

AUG, 2017 - MAY, 2021

## Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA

Some Courses: Java Programming, Data Structures Algorithms, Operating Systems, Advanced Algorithms, Calculus 2, Multivariate Calculus, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Computer Security

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

MAY. 2023 - PRESENT

# Software Engineer II - Backend, GasBuddy, Lake Ridge, VA

- Design and develop efficient database structures and queries to optimize the performance of GasBuddy's Payment services backend systems.
- Perform testing to ensure systems meet documented user requirements.
- Troubleshoot, test, and validate software issues; resolve issues with due urgency and maintain thorough documentation of all software solutions.
- · Develop and implement scalable and efficient backend solutions to support GasBuddy's platform.
- Conduct code reviews of team members' code to ensure adherence to best practices and maintain code quality standards.
- Collaborate with the team to develop and implement innovative and user-friendly solutions for GasBuddy's Payment services that enhance the customer experience
- Work with the Product Owner to prioritize and plan the development of new features for GasBuddy's Payment services
- Participate in regular team meetings to provide updates on the progress of feature development and discuss any challenges or roadblocks
- · Create and maintain technical documentation for GasBuddy's Payment services backend systems.
- Contribute to the continuous improvement of GasBuddy's Payment services backend systems by providing feedback and suggestions for enhancements and optimizations.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

JUL. 2021 - AUG. 2022

# Software Engineer - Backend, Atlassian, Mountain View, CA

- Inspired and mentored less experienced engineers and interns.
- Interviewed candidates in system design.
- Worked in a startup environment that was fast-paced, continuously changing, and with rapidly increasing responsibilities dayby-day because the team had too many high-priority projects and too few engineers.
- Built and shipped back-end API features and capabilities daily in a highly scalable, cross-geo distributed environment.
- Ensured full visibility, error reporting, and monitoring of high performing backend services and independently created and presented multiple TechOps reports.
- Developed and debugged APIs and features for Cloud Security Link's Identity And Access Management and User Provisioning microservices to scale from syncing 1000s of group memberships to 12+ million on Atlassian Access Admin customer site.
- Optimized queries for databases containing tables for users, groups, and group memberships by 500x.
- Worked with Java, Kotlin, Splunk, SignalFx, Pollinator, LaunchDarkly, pganalyze, SAML, OAuth, Okta, Microsoft Azure, User Provisioning, Agile Methodologies, PostgreSQL, and AWS stack, including security, deployment pipelines, and automation.
- Completed on-call rotations, led the team to solve major incidents, attended to customer questions about team's services and APIs, wrote documentation of common questions and answers for support engineers to reference.
- Became an expert in streamhub, shipyard, and AWS SQS resources domain and wrote technical tutorials and reference pages for teammates and new hires.
- Gained experience as a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE)
- · Demonstrated high-quality technical writing
- Managed internal and external customer requirements and expectations Gained experience defining SLOs/SLIs and implementing monitoring, alerting, and runbooks for backend services.

MAY, 2020 - AUG, 2020

# Software Engineer - Backend, Atlassian, Arlington, VA

- Migrate user provisioning REST API load tests from Gatling, which is written in Scala, to our internal testing tool written in Python to execute 1000+ requests per minute per HTTP method.
- Simulate 1000, 2000, and 5000 users. Test GET, POST, PUT, PATCH, and DELETE types of APIs. Monitor CPU and Memory use.
- Analyze data gathered from load test runs via signalFX dashboards and Splunk logs, provide sound recommendations for performance improvements, and identify bottlenecks of application.
- Improved performance of PATCH API response by 10 times.
- Cached GET API requests to relieve load on the Postgres database and to improve response times.

MAY, 2019 - AUG, 2019

## Software Product Sprint Participant - Full Stack, Google, Richmond, VA

- Collaborated with a team of peers and a Google software engineer to design and implement a swimming pool rental web application using Java, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS over the course of 10 weeks, leveraging various Google Cloud Platform APIs, including App Engine and Datastore.
- Practiced industry best practices such as: contributing to open source software using Git and GitHub, conducting code reviews with/for teammates, extending an existing codebase, participating in distributed development, designing new components and interfaces and leading them to completion.
- Built a map with a search box that finds all of the swimming pools in a specified city within a chosen country and displays markers for all of the pools returned, with on-click details for each pool using the Google Places API and Google Maps JavaScript API.

MAY, 2018 - AUG, 2018

# Associate Programmer Analyst (Contract) - Full Stack, Dominion Energy, Richmond, VA

- Designed and built an issue and assignment tracking ASP.NET and C# application for the Fault Analysis team which standardizes the process of reporting accidents that occur at company substations and managing employees' progress to resolve issues and prevent future problems.
- Coordinated weekly meetings with the team to present project scope, goals, and deliverables to ensure consistency with company strategy and commitments.
- Delivered comprehensive documentation of project development and subsequent revisions to include insights from all stakeholders and ensure that future developers can understand and maintain the application.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

SEP. 2017 - DEC. 2017

## Research Assistant - Full Stack, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA

- Worked 7 nights per week for free while attending full-load of university math, computer science, and physical sciences courses.
- Collaborated with graduate students to develop a web tool for users to quickly identify diseases that influence other diseases.
- Developed color-coded network visualizations using D3.js to visualize connections between specific disease miRNAs.
- Managed large databases that support web applications using SQL and PHP on phpMyAdmin.

MAY, 2017 - JUN, 2017

## Frontend Web Developer, Yobbz, Arlington, VA

- Worked and logged 17-18 hours per weekday for free for a startup company during senior experience which was last couple months of high school.
- Engineered the company's website content and improved its functionality and design using HTML5, CSS, and jQuery.
- Conferred with the company owner to prioritize needs, resolve conflicts, develop content criteria, and choose solutions.
- Reduced team's product development time by creating an interactive mobile application prototype for the developers to reference.

## **SKILLS**

Java, Kotlin, Microservices, REST APIs, High Performance Computing (HPC), gRPC, SAML, OAuth, Query Optimization, Load Testing, C++, Python, Spring Framework, Amazon Web Services (AWS), C, Python, XML, Django, Ruby on Rails, Golang / Go, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), NoSQL, MongoDB, Scala, Linux, Web Development, Stripe, Bash, Node.js, AWS Lambda, PHP, Swift, Android, JavaScript, Front-End Development, SQL, HTML, React.js, Git, MySQL, Jira, PostgreSQL, Microsoft Azure, CSS, D3.js, Back-End Web Development, Programming, Databases, Software Development, Object-Oriented Programming, Docker, Kafka, Kubernetes, JVM, Maven, Jenkins, RESTful web services, Java libraries, CMS, J2EE, JavaEE, Spring, JUnit, Hibernate, Ruby, Memcached, OWASP, Android App Development, Slack, Terraform, LESS, SASS, Redis, Simple Queue Service, Flask, Tableau, DevOps, Bamboo, Spinnaker